Alysa Truong

Information Technology Solutions Intern

Philadelphia, PA

215-906-7194

□ alytruong@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/alysa-truong

alytruong.github.io

An entry-level web development position that utilizes my technical skills, education, business experience and passion for solving interesting problems and transforming complication into simplicity. Strong background in technical support, attention to detail, and a drive for continuous knowledge and improvements in development.

Education

TEMPLE UNIVERSITY

AUG 2011 - DEC 2016

TEMPLE UNIVERSITY

AUG 2015 - DEC 2016

UNIVERSITY OF ST. ANDREWS

SEP 2014 - DEC 2014

REINVESTMENT FUND

MAY 2016 - DEC 2017

Bachelor of Science, Information Science & Technology

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

GPA: 3.29, Dean's List: Fall 2011

Certificate, Computer Security & Digital Forensics

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

Introduction to Criminal Justice, Computer Network & Security, Introduction to Digital Forensics

IFSA-Butler Study Abroad Program, Computer & Informatics Science

St. Andrews, Scotland

The Internet and the Web: Concepts and Programming, Human Computer Interactions

Work Experiences

Information Technology Solutions Intern

Provided end-user support to employees in identifying, diagnosing, and resolving computer and equipment challenges for Philadelphia, Baltimore, and Atlanta offices. Enhanced and maintained multiple network diagrams in VISIO.

- Implemented organization's private code repository server and configured low-level settings for data analysis team.
- Designed and delivered presentations, demonstrations, and workshops on git and GitLab that train 10 users within IT and Policy Solution departments.
- Drafted, finalized and maintained GitLab server manuals for Operational and Maintenance procedures.

TEMPLE UNIVERSITY IS&T CAPSTONE PROJECT

JAN 2016 - DEC 2016

Student Learning Assessment Manager (SLAM)

Devised a web reporting system that administers, records, and monitors student learning assessments for 400+ degree programs within Temple University's Institutional Research & Assessment (IR&A)

- Utilized an Object-oriented Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) approach with Unified Modeling Language (UML) tools and reviewed VISIO documents with client.
- Followed an Agile Development Process that includes multiple Sprints and completing weekly scrum reports for Scrum meetings.
- Coded the Faculty member home page using C# and SQL in Visual Studio and MS SQL, using git and GitHub for code management.
- Developed Test Plans and executed system testing as an individual, a team, and with client.
- Prepared all final system documentation including 50+ pages User Manuals and Operation procedures.

CITY HALL OF PHILADELPHIA

MAY 2014 - AUG 2014

Research Intern

Supported developments of Philadelphia's first annual PHL Live Center Stage Music Competition that provides local musicians and artists a platform to exhibit their talents. Collected data on potential artists, judges, and venues and created spreadsheets based on these datasets. Promoted event to local musicians and venues through phone calls and emails.

Skills

Languages

C#, SQL, Java, HTML & CSS, Bootstrap, ASP.NET, JavaScript, AngularJS, ¡Query, WinForms

Workflows

Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Wallfall/Agile, Scrum

Databases

MySQL, MS SQL Server, MS Access

Applications/Platforms

Visual Studio, Git, GitHub/GitLab, Netbeans, Asana, JIRA, Windows, Mac OS X, Linux (Ubuntu)